American Academy of Psychiatry and the Law Records
Oskar Diethelm Library
American Academy of Psychiatry and the Law Records
1969 - 1989
This collection contains records from the American Academy of Psychiatry and the Law. The collection has no series and needs to be reprocessed.
1.83 linear feet (3 boxes)
American Academy of Psychiatry and the Law
Oskar Diethelm Library DeWitt Wallace Institute of Psychiatry: History, Policy and the Arts Weill Cornell Medical College 525 East 68th Street, Box 140 New York, NY 10065
1986.0001
Unknown.
This collection is open for research.
Founded in 1969, the American Academy of Psychiatry and the Law (AAPL) is an organization of psychiatrists dedicated to excellence in practice, teaching, and research in forensic psychiatry.
American Academy of Psychiatry and the Law; American Board of Forensic Psychiatry
Arranged primarily chronologically by the type or topic of the materials, including Early History and Founding, By-Laws, Membership and Directories, American Board of Forensic Psychiatry, Newsletters, Bulletins, Correspondence, Executive Committee and Busi­ness Meetings, Scientific Papers, the Patuxent Experience, the Tri-State District Chapter, Financial Data, and Conventions. The collection has no series and needs to be reprocessed.
- No series
  - The early history and foundations of AAPL, including correspondence, Undated (Box 1)
  - Newsletter, 1976 - 1985 (Box 1)
  - By-laws, Undated (Box 1)
  - Membership, Undated (Box 1)
  - The American Board of Forensic Psychiatry, Undated (Box 1)
  - Bulletins, Undated (Box 1)
  - 1971 correspondence (Box 1)
  - 1972 correspondence and rights to treatment (Box 1)
  - 1973 correspondence (Box 1)
  - 1974 correspondence (Box 1)
  - 1975 correspondence (Box 1)
  - 1976 correspondence (Box 1)
  - 1977 correspondence (Box 1)
  - 1978 correspondence (Box 1)
  - 1979 correspondence (Box 1)
  - 1980 correspondence (Box 1)
  - 1981 correspondence (Box 1)
  - 1982 correspondence (Box 1)
  - 1983 correspondence (Box 1)
  - 1984 correspondence (Box 1)
  - 1985 correspondence (Box 1)
  - 1986-1989 correspondence (Box 1)
  - Minutes of meeting and reference data, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of meeting, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of executive committee meeting, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of executive committee meeting, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of executive committee meeting, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of executive committee meeting, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of executive committee and business meeting, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of executive committee and business meeting, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of executive committee and business meeting, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Minutes of executive committee and business meeting, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Patuxent summary data, Undated (Box 1)
  - Patuxent extended data, Undated (Box 1)
  - New Patuxent legislation, Undated (Box 1)
  - Patuxent extended data and correspondence, Undated (Box 1)
  - New York State Group, Undated; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Teaching Day, Adequacy in Forensic Psychiatric Examinations, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Finance, Undated (Box 1)
  - 1981 annual convention (Box 1)
  - 1982 annual convention (Box 1)
  - 1983 annual convention (Box 1)
  - 1984 annual convention (Box 1)
  - 1985 annual convention (Box 1)
  - 1986 annual convention (Box 1)
  - 1988 annual convention (Box 1)
  - 1989 annual convention (Box 1)
  - State of California Department of Corrections and Forensic Psychiatry, Undated (Box 1)
  - Membership directories, 1972; 1975 - 1976; 1978; 1980 - 1985 (Box 2)
  - Stationary, Undated (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous data and announcements, Undated (Box 2)
  - Old membership data, Undated (Box 2)
  - Efforts to arrange joint or simultaneous meetings with American Academy of Child Psychiatry, Undated (Box 2)
  - 1979 annual meeting cassettes (Box 3)